Okay. Let's get into working with CSS grid itself.
حسنًا. لننتقل إلى الحديث عن شبكة CSS
CSS grid is a two-dimensional design system for the web,
شبكة CSS هي نظام تصميم ثنائي الأبعاد للويب،
which means you can organize content layout into rows and columns,
ويعني هذا أن بوسعنا تنظيم المحتوى في صفوف وأعمدة
which really means you can do almost anything.
وبالتالي يمكن عمل أي شيء تقريبًا.
Rows and columns come together to make areas,
تتلاقي الصفوف والأعمدة معاً لتشكل مساحات
which can be named.
يمكن تسميتها.
Oh my, CSS grid,
يتضمن العمل بشبكة CSS
there is so much fun to be had.
الكثير من المرح والمتعة.
But we need to start with the basics.
لكن علينا أن نبدأ من الأساسيات.
Everything starts with rows and columns.
يبدأ كل شيء من الصفوف والأعمدة.
After setting the display property of your container grid,
وبعد ضبط خاصية عرض الحاوية على شبكة،
your container div to grid,
وتحويل أقسام الحاوية (div) إلى شبكة،
the next step is to set the rows and columns in your grid,
تتمثل الخطوة التالية في ضبط الصفوف والأعمدة في في الشبكة،
which can be done with the CSS properties, grid template columns,
وذلك باستخدام خصائص CSS وهي أعمدة قالب الشبكة (grid-template-columns)،
grid template rows, and if you see here,
وصفوف قالب الشبكة (grid-template-rows)،
grid gap defines the distance in between each row and column.
وفراغ الشبكة (grid gap) هذا يحدد المسافة الفاصلة بين كل صف وعمود.
So in this example,
في هذا المثال،
we would have two columns,
لدينا عمودان،
two rows, and each of them would be separated by 15 pixels.
وصفّان، تفصل بينهما مسافة 15 بيكسل.
That's what we call the gutter between the rows and columns.
وهذا ما نُسميه الهامش الفاصل بين الصفوف والأعمدة.
Let's see an example of what rows and columns and CSS grid looked like in the real world.
لنرَ مثالًا يُظهر كيف تبدو الصفوف والأعمدة وشبكة CSS في التطبيق العملي.